Guide to the Adolph M. Foerster Collection, 1868-1923 CAM.FOER.2015
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Printed Music, II.
  - Opus 80 Love visions, 1922 (Box 12, Folder 203)
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: Harp, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203v)
  - Opus 81 American ode, 1922 (Box 12, Folder 205)
    Leipzig: Fritz Schuberth. Score and parts. Plate no. 45
    - Opus 81 American ode: score, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205a)
    - Opus 81 American ode: 1st violin, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205b)
    - Opus 81 American ode: 2nd violin, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205c)
    - Opus 81 American ode: viola, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205d)
    - Opus 81 American ode: cello, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205e)
    - Opus 81 American ode: bass, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205f)
    - Opus 81 American ode: piccolo, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205g)
    - Opus 81 American ode: tuba (Box 12, Item 205h)
    - Opus 81 American ode: 1st flute, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205i)
    - Opus 81 American ode: 2nd oboe, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205j)
    - Opus 81 American ode: 2nd flute, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205k)
    - Opus 81 American ode: 1st oboe, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205l)
    - Opus 81 American ode: 1st clarinet, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205m)
    - Opus 81 American ode: 2nd bassoon, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205n)
    - Opus 81 American ode: 2nd clarinet, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205o)
    - Opus 81 American ode: 1st bassoon, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205p)
    - Opus 81 American ode: 1st horn, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205q)
    - Opus 81 American ode: 4th horn, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205r)
    - Opus 81 American ode: 2nd horn, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205s)
    - Opus 81 American ode: 3rd horn, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205t)
    - Opus 81 American ode: 1st trumpet, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205u)
    - Opus 81 American ode: 2nd trombone, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205v)
    - Opus 81 American ode: 2nd trumpet, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205w)
    - Opus 81 American ode: 1st trombone, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205x)
    - Opus 81 American ode: 3rd trombone, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205y)
    - Opus 81 American ode: snare drum, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205z)
    - Opus 81 American ode: tympani, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205aa)
    - Opus 81 American ode: beck gr.tr, 1922 (Box 12, Item 205bb)
  - Opus 84 no. 2 Homage to Mozart, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 216)
    Philadelphia: Theodore Presser. Piano score. Plate no. 16202.
  - Opus 85 The Enchanter's dream, 1922 (Box 13, Folder 221)
    Leipzig: Fritz Schuberth, Jr. Orchestra score and parts. Plate no. 46
    - Opus 85 The Enchanter's dream: score (Box 13, Item 221a)
    - Opus 85 The Enchanter's dream: 1st violin (Box 13, Item 221b)
    - Opus 85 The Enchanter's dream: 2nd violin (Box 13, Item 221c)
    - Opus 85 The Enchanter's dream: viola (Box 13, Item 221d)
    - Opus 85 The Enchanter's dream: bass (Box 13, Item 221c)
  - Opus 17 no. 1 Romanza, Opus 17 no. 2 Melodie, Opus 26 Novelette, Opus 36 no. 1 Novelette, Opus 36 no. 3 Duo (Box 13, Folder 226)
    - Opus 17 no. 1 Romanza, 1885 (Box 13, Folder 226.01)
      New York: J.O. von Prochazka, 1885, score and parts, violin and piano, Plate no. 350
      - Opus 17 no. 1 Romanza: score, 1885 (Box 13, Item 226.01a)
      - Opus 17 no. 1 Romanza: violin (Box 13, Item 226.01b)
    - Opus 17 no. 2 Melodie (Box 13, Folder 226.02)
      Leipzig: Fritz Schuberth, Jr., 1891. score and parts, violin and piano. Plate no. 1883
      - Opus 17 no. 2 Melodie: score, 1891 (Box 13, Item 226.02a)
      - Opus 17 no. 2 Melodie: violin (Box 13, Item 226.02b)
    - Opus 26 Novelette, 1890 (Box 13, Item 226.03)
      New York: Edward Schuberth & Co. Score and part. Plate no. G29T: See 48A
    - Opus 36 no. 1 Novelette, 1895 (Box 13, Item 226.04)
      Leipzig: Breitkopf & Hartel. Score and parts. Plate no. 21119: See 70A
    - Opus 36 no. 3 Duo, 1895 (Box 13, Item 226.05)
      Leipzig: Breitkopf & Hartel. Plate no. 21121. Bound in orange linen cover with gamble hinge. Part book separate, same cover and extra part of opus 15, Fantasie.: See 71A
  - Opus 15 Fantasie, Opus 17 no. 1 Romance, Opus 17 no. 2 Melodie, Opus 26 Novelette, Opus 35 no. 1 Novelette, Opus 36 no. 2 Intermezzo, Opus 36 no. 3 Duo (Box 13, Folder 227)
    - Opus 15 Fantasie, 1885 (Box 13, Folder 227.01)
      Score and part. New York: J.O. von Prochazka. Plate no 200.
      - Opus 15 Fantasie: score, 1885 (Box 13, Item 227.01a)
      - Opus 15 Fantasie: violin, 1885 (Box 13, Item 227.01b)
    - Opus 17 no. 1 Romance, 1891 (Box 13, Item 227.02)
      Leipzig: Fritz Schuberth, Jr. Plate no. 1882. Revised edition.:See 17A
    - Opus 17 no. 2 Melodie, 1891 (Box 13, Item 227.03)
      Leipzig: Fritz Schuberth, Jr. Plate no. 1883: See 226B
    - Opus 26 Novelette, 1890 (Box 13, Folder 227.04)
      Leipzig: Fritz Schuberth, Jr. Plate no G29T: See 48A
    - Opus 35 no. 1 Novelette, 1895 (Box 13, Item 227.05)
      Leipzig: Breitkopf & Hartel.
    - Opus 36 no. 2 Intermezzo, 1895 (Box 13, Folder 227.06)
      Leipzig: Breitkopf & Hartel. Plate no. 21120.
      - Opus 36 no. 2 Intermezzo: score, 1895 (Box 13, Item 227.06a)
      - Opus 36 no. 2 Intermezzo: violin, 1895 (Box 13, Item 227.06b)
    - Opus 36 no. 3 Duo, 1895 (Box 13, Folder 227.07)
      Leipzig: Breitkopf & Hartel. Plate no. 21121. This item bound in heavy blue paper cover with gamble hinge.: See 71A
      - Opus 36 no. 3 Duo: score, 1895 (Box 13, Item 227.07a)
      - Opus 36 no. 3 Duo: violin, 1895 (Box 13, Item 227.07b)
  - Lead, kindly light, 1907 (Box 14, Folder 273)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber. Solo, chorus and organ score. Plate no. 15.
  - O worship the king, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 278)
    Philadelphia: Theodore Presser. Solo, chorus, and organ score. Plate no. 20793
  - When all thy mercies, 1904 (Box 14, Folder 279)
    New York: Hinds & Noble. Solo, chorus, and organ score.
  - Ave Maria, 1903 (Box 14, Folder 282)
    Cincinnati: John Church & Co. Score and parts. voice, violin, piano and organ obbligato. Plate no. 14359.
    - Ave Maria: score, 1905 (Box 14, Item 282a)
    - Ave Maria: organ, 1905 (Box 14, Item 282b)
    - Ave Maria: violin, 1905 (Box 14, Item 282c)
  - Auf Offner See, 1868 (Box 15, Folder 291)
    Pittsburg: Gazette Gebarbe. Score 54 pages.
  - 6 Soliloquies for the Piano No. 1 Retrospect, 1888 (Box 15, Folder 292)
    Chicago: Lyon & Healy. Piano score. 2 copies. One copy signed by Pratt.
  - 6 Soliloquies for the Piano No. 2 Morituri Salutamus, 1888 (Box 15, Folder 293)
    Chicago: Lyon & Healy. Piano score.
  - 6 Soliloquies for the Piano No. 3 After the Ballet, 1888 (Box 15, Folder 294)
  - 6 Soliloquies for the Piano No. 4 Intermezzo-Sostenuto, 1888 (Box 15, Folder 295)
  - 6 Soliloquies for the Piano No. 5 Antique Dance, 1888 (Box 15, Folder 296)
  - 6 Soliloquies for the Piano No. 6 The Silent Deep, 1888 (Box 15, Folder 297)
    Chicago: Lyon & Healy.
  - Eros, 1890 (Box 15, Folder 298)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber & Bro. Piano score. cover only
  - Ave Verum, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 301)
    Arranged by Theodore Finney. Pittsburg: Volkwein Bros. SATB. Published as part of the University of Pittsburgh Choral series
  - Exaltation Prelude in C, 1910 (Box 15, Folder 302)
    New York: Edward Schuberth & Co. Organ score.
  - Prelude in Ab, 1905 (Box 15, Folder 303)
    Boston: Oliver Ditson Co. Organ score.
  - Ave Verum: Proof score (Box 15, Folder 305)
    SATB arrangement by Theodore Finney with pencilled corrections.
  - Where Go the Boats Op. 7 No. 1, 1909 (Box 15, Folder 306)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber & Bro. Lyrics from Robert Louis Stevenson's Child's Garden of Verses
  - Op. 32 Sonate, 1898 (Box 15, Folder 307)
    Leipzig: Breitkopf & Hartel. handwritten dedication on cover "To Adolf [sic] M. Foerster with Compliment of Ernst R. Kroeger July 18, 1904"
    - Op. 32 Sonate: score, 1898 (Box 15, Item 307)
    - Op. 32 Sonate: violin, 1898 (Box 15, Item 307b)
  - These are They, 1903 (Box 15, Folder 308)
    New York: G. Schirmer. SATB organ. handwritten dedication on cover "For Adolph Foerster from the author"
  - Binder's volume 73 (Box 15, Folder 309)
    Housed separate from the Foerster collection in the archive at the Center for American Music. Labeled Binder's Volume #73.
    - Binder's Volume 73: A Wreath of Songs Op. 70, 1910 (Box 15, Item 309a)
      New York: Jerome H. Remick & Co. With Moonlight Beaming; Finland Love Song; Cupid Armed; Oh Fair, O Pure!; Nubian Girl's Song; Hidden Love
    - Binder's volume 73: Three Songs, 1877 (Box 15, Item 309b)
      Philadelphia: T.A. Bacher. 1. O Thou Art Like a Flower 2. Thou Pretty Fishermaiden 3. With Tear Thro' the Forest I Wander
    - Binder's volume 73: Fur eine Singllimme mit Begleitung des Claviers (Box 15, Item 309c)
      Leipzig: C.F. Kahnt. Gleich und Gleich (The Star); Wehmuth (Melancholy); Im Rhein, im heiligen Strome (The Rhine); Hor ich das Liedchen klingen (On hearing the strains enthralling); Meeresstille (The Ocean at Rest); So wand'l ich wieder den alten Weg (Once more my steps): See 2A
    - Binder's volume 73: Three Songs Op. 12 The Mists, 1882 (Box 15, Item 309d)
      New York: Edward Schuberth & Co.
    - Binder's volume 73: Three Songs Op. 12 Fairy Tale, 1882 (Box 15, Item 309e)
    - Binder's volume 73: Two Songs Op. 34, 1892 (Box 15, Item 309f)
      Pittsburg: H. Kleber & Bro. I saw thee weep; Adoration
    - Binder's volume 73: Three Songs Op. 42 No. 1 Autumn Leaves, 1897 (Box 15, Item 309g)
      Leipzig: Fritz Schuberth, Jr.
    - Binder's volume 73: Three Songs Op. 42 No. 3 By the Sea-Side, 1897 (Box 15, Item 309h)
    - Binder's volume 73: Four Songs Op. 43 No. 1 The Grecian Isles, 1897 (Box 15, Item 309i)
    - Binder's volume 73: Four Songs Op. 43 No. 2. She Walks in Beauty, 1897 (Box 15, Item 309j)
      Pittsburgh: H. Kleber & Bro.
    - Binder's volume 73: Four Songs Op. 43 No. 3. Shepherd's Lament, 1897 (Box 15, Item 309k)
    - Binder's volume 73: Four Songs Op. 43 No. 4 When Thou Art Nigh, 1897 (Box 15, Item 309l)
    - Binder's volume 73: Six Songs Op. 49 No. 1 Night in the Desert, 1900 (Box 15, Item 309m)
    - Binder's volume 73: Fair Rosalind, 1900 (Box 15, Item 309n)
    - Binder's volume 73: Six Songs Op. 49 No. 4 A Hunting Song, 1900 (Box 15, Item 309o)
    - Binder's volume 73: Six Songs Op. 49 No. 5 Unfathomable Sea, 1900 (Box 15, Item 309p)
    - Binder's volume 73: Six Songs Op. 49 No. 6 A Sleeping Child, 1900 (Box 15, Item 309q)
      PIttsburg: H. Kleber & Bro.
    - Binder's volume 73: Sleep Little Darling, Proposal, 1900 (Box 15, Item 309r)
    - Binder's volume 73: Oh Fairest of the rural Maids, 1900 (Box 15, Item 309s)
    - Binders volume 73: Serenade, 1900 (Box 15, Item 309t)
    - Binder's volume 73: Selected Songs for Medium Voice, 1912 (Box 15, Item 309u)
      NY: G. Schirmer 1. The Daisy Op. 30 No. 3 2. At Night Op. 69 No. 1 3. The Furtree Op. 57 No. 2 4. In March Op. 69 No. 5 5. The Water-lily Op. 53 No. 2 6. An Old Melody Op. 53 No. 4 7. Love Seemeth Terrible Op. 53 No. 5; 8. The Robin's Lullaby Op. 64 No. 4 9. Nights of Music Op. 53 No. 9; 10. After the Revel Op. 63 No. 8; 11. Those Eyes of Thin Op. 73 No. 2; 12. Song of Hope Op. 78 No. 1; 13. Russian Lover's Song Op. 78 No. 2; 14. When Evening Shades Op. 78 No. 3
    - Binder's volume 73: Call to Charon, 1924 (Box 15, Item 309v)
    - Binder's volume 73: Six Songs, 1909 (Box 15, Item 309w)
      Pittsburg: H. Kleber & Bro. Unceasing Love; Ein Fichtenbaum (The Fir Tree); Fruhzeitiger Fruhling (Early Spring); Forester's Song; Der Lenz ist da! (Spring is Here)
    - Binder's volume 73: Greek Love Songs, 1906 (Box 15, Item 309x)
      Pittsburg: H. Kleber & Bro. 1. Time's Revenges 2. Love in the wine 3. The light of Love 4. Bittersweet 5. Rekindling the Flame 6. Purity of love 7. Kiss within the cup 8. After the revel 9. Love aflame
    - Binder's volume 73: Garland of Songs, Part I, 1906 (Box 15, Item 309y)
      Pittsburg: H. Kleber & Bro. 1. Song of the soul (Golder) 2. The starless night (Golder) 3. The Starlit night (Golder) 4. The robin's lullaby (Golder) 5. 'Tis the last rose of summer (Moore) 6. The silent sea (Coleridge)
    - Binder's volume 73: Garland of Songs, Part II, 1906 (Box 15, Item 309z)
      Pittsburg: H. Kleber & Bro. 7. To the beloved (Roxby) 8. Love me if I live (Cornwall) 9. Heart Song (Deane) 10. Love alone (Moore) 11. Enraptured (Byron) 12 Sun of the sleepless (Byron)
    - Binder's volume 73: Four Love Songs, 1908 (Box 15, Item 309aa)
      Pittsburg: H. Kleber & Bro. 1. I love thee (Hood) 2. Love thee, dearest? (Moore) 3. Love's litany (Bruce) 4. To see thee, to love thee (Moore)
    - Binder's volume 73: Child-Lyrics, 1909 (Box 15, Item 309bb)
      Pittsburg: H. Kleber & Bro. Where go the boats?; Fairy Bread; Song of Bed-time; The Friendly Cow; The Swing
    - Binder's volume 73: Second Album of Lyrics Part I, 1909 (Box 15, Item 309cc)
      Pittsburg: H. Kleber & Bro. Twilight Reverie; Swan Song; Love; Absolved; Midnight Reverie; A Tear; Withered Flowers; Where e'er I am; If Thou Must Depart
    - Binder's volume 73: Second Album of Lyrics Part II, 1909 (Box 15, Item 309dd)
      Pittsburg: H. Kleber & Bro. At Night; Row gently, my Gondolier; Longing; Through the Wood; In March; Inquiry; Evening Love Song
    - Binder's volume 73: Op. 72 Enslaved, A blight has fallen, 1910 (Box 15, Item 309ee)
    - Binder's volume 73: Op. 75 Alone, Here Sleeps the Bard, 1911 (Box 15, Item 309ff)
    - Binder's volume 73: Op. 74 The Indian Maid, Calm be thy sleep, 1911 (Box 15, Item 309gg)
    - Binder's volume 73: Op. 76 No. 1 Song of the Woods, 1911 (Box 15, Item 309hh)
      New York: Carl Fischer
    - Binder's volume 73: Op. 76 No. 2 A Dream, 1911 (Box 15, Item 309ii)
      New York: Carl Fisher.
    - Binder's volume 73: Op. 80 Love Visions, 1922 (Box 15, Item 309jj)
    - Binder's volume 73: Serenade from "The Spanish Student", 1879 (Box 15, Item 309kk)
      Published by W.F. Shaw
    - Binder's volume 73: O Love Long Ago, 1890 (Box 15, Item 309ll)
      New York: Edgar S. Werner.
  - Unfurl the Starry Flag, 1898 (Box 16, Folder 311)
    New York: J. Remington Fairlamb. inscribed to Foerster by the author.
  - A Christmas Carol: The Desert and the Wilderness, 1898 (Box 16, Folder 312)
  - Op.68. Sunday in Spring, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 363)
    Pittsburgh: Volkwein. Piano and chorus.
  - Compositions by Adolf M. Foerster (Box 16, Folder 364)
    Various sizes. Collection of printed sheets titled "Compositions by Adolph M. Foerster," updated in Foerster's hand. There are 4 different pages, each representing a different level of compositional output.
- Articles, periodicals, catalogs and newspaper clippings, III.
  - Patriotism in Song, Feb. 19, 1899 (Box 16, Folder 321A)
    Newspaper clipping. Originally published in The Cincinnati Enquirer.
  - Patriotism in Song, Feb. 19, 1899 (Box 16, Folder 321)
    from The Cincinnati Enquirer.
  - A Remarkable group of artists (Box 16, Folder 322)
    Photo from the Musical Courtier of "guests present at a dinner recently given by Mr. And Mrs. Arthur M. Abell at the Berlin Home of the Musical Courier." Foerster included but not identified.
  - Gin Sanger des Odenwaldes (Box 16, Folder 323)
    German newspaper clipping (relevance unclear). In German.
  - Local Composer's Christmas Music (Box 16, Folder 324)
    clipping from unidentified Pittsburgh Newspaper. Includes photo of Foerster.
  - Variations (Box 16, Folder 325)
    Clipping from The Musical Courier. Article by the editor-in-chief about the writers of America's songs; mentions Foerster
  - Europe Adds to Pittsburg's Finest, Sept. 10, 1898 (Box 16, Folder 326)
    Clipping from The Pittsburg Dispatch. Article about donations to Pittsburgh library; article mentions Foerster and his Dedication March.
  - H. Kleber & Bro Recent Musical Publications of Interest (Box 16, Folder 327)
    Catalog for H. Kleber & Bro., includes Foerster materials for sale.
  - Reminiscences, October, 1921 (Box 16, Folder 328)
    Issue of The Musical Forecast that contains an article by Foerster.
  - The Musician, April, 1896 (Box 16, Folder 329)
    Includes an article about Foerster, "Adolph Martin Foerster" includes pull-out photo supplement of Foerster.: entire Journal scanned
  - Adolph M. Foerster and His Musical Compositions, June, 1911 (Box 16, Folder 330)
    written by George Mortimer Brush. article about Foerster, "Adolph M. Foerster and his Vocal compositions": entire Journal scanned
  - Outline of the Musical History in Pittsburgh, January, 1923 (Box 16, Folder 331)
    article by Foerster, part 1, in The Musical Forecast.
  - Outlines of Musical History, February, 1923 (Box 16, Folder 332)
    article by Foerster, part 2, in The Musical Forecast.
  - Outlines of Musical History in Pittsburgh, March, 1923 (Box 16, Folder 333)
    article by Foerster, part 3, in The Musical Forecast.
  - Musical History in Pittsburgh, April, 1923 (Box 16, Folder 334)
    article by Foerster, part 4, in The Musical Forecast.
  - Musical History in Pittsburgh, May, 1923 (Box 16, Folder 335)
    article by Foerster, part 5, from The Musical Forecast.
  - Musical History in Pittsburgh, August, 1923 (Box 16, Folder 336)
    article by Foerster, part 6, in The Musical Forecast.
  - Musical History in Pittsburgh, September, 1923 (Box 16, Folder 337)
    article by Foerster, concluded, in The Musical Forecast.
  - Players for the Fest: The 60 selections as made by the music committee (Box 16, Folder 357)
    clipping from unidentified paper. Mentions Foerster
  - New Music Hall is Pleasing to Musicians: Improvements Aid to Performers and Theodore Thomas Orchestra Makes a Hit, Aug. 28, 1907 (Box 16, Folder 358)
    mentions Foerster and his "Dedication March"
  - Closing Mozart Concerts: Two Grand Programs for Tomorrow and Friday Nights, May 9, 1894 (Box 16, Folder 359)
    Mentions an upcoming performance of Foerster's "Falconers"
  - [untitled] newspaper clipping (Box 16, Folder 360)
    Quotes Foerster regarding Pittsburgh orchestra.
  - [untitled] newspaper clippings (Box 16, Folder 361)
    mentions Foerster
  - The Music World (Box 16, Folder 362)
- Photos, IV.
  - Photo of D. Beddoe, 1905 (Box 16, Folder 338)
    inscribed to Foerster by Bedoe.
  - Photo of Marie Rappold, Jan. 25, 1907 (Box 16, Folder 339)
    inscribed to Foerster by Rappold.
  - photo of unidentified man (Box 16, Folder 340)
  - Photo of Adolph M. Foerster (Box 16, Folder 341)
    Photo of Foerster seated at piano
  - photo of unidentified man (Box 16, Folder 342)
  - photo of Emil Senger Basso (Box 16, Folder 343)
  - photo of Otto Hegner, November 1876 (Box 16, Folder 344)
    inscribed to Foerster by Henger.
  - photo of Marienbad (Box 16, Folder 345)
  - Postcard with Liszt's image & carte de visite w/photo of Lizst (Box 16, Folder 346)
  - Images of Emma Loeffler, 1910 (Box 16, Folder 347)
    3 postcards, 1 postcard inscribed "Emma Loeffler Queen of Sheba." 1 photo inscribed to Foerster by Loeffler, Dublin, 1910.
  - Photo of [?] Artur Clasper (Box 16, Folder 348)
    inscribed to Foerster by Clasper
  - group photo of Bangor Symphony Orchestra, July 21, 1902 (Box 16, Folder 349)
    inscribed on back
  - photo of Robert Shallon at piano, 1896 (Box 16, Folder 350)
    inscribed on back to Foerster from Shallon
  - photo of Gilda Barnes Wood (Box 16, Folder 351)
    inscribed by Barnes Wood to Foerster
  - Photo of Painting of Foerster as a child, by his father (Box 16, Folder 352)
  - Group photo of many musicians including Foerster (Box 16, Folder 353)
    some identities on back
  - Photo of Adolph M. Foerster as an old man (Box 16, Folder 354)
  - Photo of Hand St., Pittsburgh, showing location of the apartment Foerster was born in, 1878 (Box 16, Folder 355)
  - Group of musicians, including Foerster, at La Porte, IN (Box 16, Folder 356)
    several sitters identified on back of photo.
- Correspondence and Notes, V.
  - Letter to Adolph M. Foerster (Box 16, Folder 313)
    From Washington DC. Letter from the Federal Lithograph company touting an inexpensive method for reproduction Foerster's scores.
  - Letter to "Franz", April 2, 1875 (Box 16, Folder 314)
    Leipzig. 2 pages in German.
  - Letter to "Franz", Aug. 1874 (Box 16, Folder 315)
    Leipzig. 2 page letter. In German.
  - Letter to "Franz", April 6, 1875 (Box 16, Folder 316)
    From Leipzig. In German: contains a blank page between the first and second pages of the letter.
  - Compositions by Adolph M. Foerster (Box 16, Folder 365)
    Collection of handwritten lists containing Foerster's works (in his hand). Each includes a different level of compositional output. Collection also includes 8 copies of a type script list (also updated in Foerster's hand). 1 list includes short biography of the composer (only one typed script is scanned)
  - Narrative to "Prelude to Goethe's Faust" (Box 16, Folder 366)
    Type script sheet giving a narrative of Foerster's "Prelude to Goethe's Faust"
  - Performances of Festival March, Op. 32 (Box 16, Folder 367)
    List of Performances for "Festival March, Op. 32." ! Copy updates in Foerster's hand
  - Notes (Box 16, Folder 368)
    Various sizes. Collection of Notes in Foerster's hand, relating to his compositions. The majority of this collection includes changes and/or corrections the composer wanted to make to his scores. References to date of composition and poems incorporated are also included.
- Programs, VI.
  - An Evening of Reading and Music (Box 16, Folder 317)
    4 pages. Program of a concert by the Mifflin Avenue M.E. Sunday School with "Mr. Foerster" on the piano
  - Twenty-Fifth Anniversary Ladies Aid Society of the South Side Hospital, April 29, 1915 (Box 16, Folder 318)
    1 page. Program of concert for the Ladies Aid Society.
  - Wagnerian Opera Festival, April 25 -28, 1923 (Box 16, Folder 319)
    10 pages. Program for the Wagnerian Festival at Schenley Theatre, Pittsburgh.
  - Manuscript Society of New York First Public Concert Ninth Season, December 15, 1897 (Box 16, Folder 320)
    7 pages. Seidl Grand Orchestra in Concert, performing, among other things, Foerster's "Hero and Leander."